Austin Chia Cheng En

E-mail: austin.chia.ce@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/austin-chia/ | Portfolio: austinchia.netlify.app | Tableau Public: public.tableau.com/profile/austin.chia.cheng.en GitHub: github.com/austinchia

Professional Summary

I am a Final-Year NTU student with previous experience in analytics and business intelligence in healthcare. A personable, self-driven and adaptable person, I am comfortable with working independently and collaborating in a team. With a strong interest in healthcare transformation, I have previous experience in a healthcare startup and have also worked in similar small firms in data analytics. I am adept in R, Tableau, MS Excel and SQL.

Work Experience

Data Analyst (Part-Time) (Aug 2020 - Present)

Speedoc Pte Ltd

- Extracted and transformed data for 6 monthly reports from MySQL database using Python and SQL, reducing processing time by 200%
- Developed 9 interactive Tableau dashboards from multi-source data
- Queried and processed app data from NoSQL database (MongoDB) for operations optimization
- Automated data extraction from digital marketing and clinic data sources to Google Sheets, saving 10+ hours/week
- Compiled ad-hoc reports from web-scraped data, app performance and HCW optimization
- Monitor reporting of app-related metrics and KPIs on Google Sheets

Data Analytics Intern

(Mar 2020 - Aug 2020)

Speedoc Pte Ltd

- Initiated 6 interactive dashboards for healthcare operations optimization and insight
- Built data pipelines to connect and extract multi-source data for daily KPI metric dashboards using MySQL and Tableau
- Cleaned digital marketing data using Excel and Google Sheets for daily marketing funnel reports
- Conducted ad-hoc data analysis for cross-functional teams in operations, digital marketing and financial

Medical Services Intern (Jan 2020 - Feb 2020)

HealthServe Ltd

- Built an automated medical inventory tracking system for >2000 PPE stock on Google Sheets
- Created a dashboard report using Pivot Tables and Vlookup for monitoring PPE inventory

BioData Science Research Intern

(May 2019 - Aug 2019)

School of Biological Sciences, Nanyang Technological University

- Extracted and preprocessed RNAseq biological datasets using Bioconductor in R and conducted statistical bootstrapping of 1000 T-test iterations for significance analysis
- Evaluated model and presented findings using R Markdown to a team of 8 bio-data scientist researchers

Digital Communications and Analytics Intern

(Jan 2019 - Aug 2019)

Relief Singapore

- Managed a social media campaign on Instagram that led to a 50% increase in follower count
- Tracked and discovered insights using Instagram Analytics and Google Analytics over a 2-month period

Education

Bachelor of Science (Hons), Biological Sciences

(Aug 2017 - May 2021)

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Relevant Coursework: Data Science for Biologists, Biostatistics, High-throughput Bioinformatics

Diploma in Biomedical Science

(2012 - 2015)

Temasek Polytechnic, Singapore

Projects

Founder and Blogger

(May 2020 - Present)

AnyInstructor (anyinstructor.com)

- Researched and wrote 30 data analytics-focused content articles to-date using WordPress
- Drove >1000 pageviews/month of website SEO traffic within 6 months

Co-curricular Activities

Chairperson Freshmen Orientation Programme, School of Biological Sciences, NTU

(Oct 2018 - Oct 2019)

Directed a team of 17 leaders to successfully coordinate a school-wide event involving 150 organizing personnel and 200 participants

Awards and Certifications

- Singapore National Finalist, ASEAN Data Science Explorers Competition 2019
- Certificate of Professional Excellence, Wiley Certified Data Analyst (WCDA)

Skills

- Technical: Excel, Tableau, SQL, R, MySQL, Python, Google Sheets, Linux(Bash), Google Analytics, MongoDB
- Languages: English, Mandarin, Thai (Basic)